Michael Hamm

Middleboro, Massachusetts, United States



mjhamm@bu.edu



linkedin.com/in/michael-hamm-001

Summary

5 years total of Software Engineering experience, with 4 years in a Professional environment.

Experienced in the ability to read and write fluently in both Java and Kotlin with an advanced understanding of the Android Development Environment.

Successfully shipped and delivered profitable features that were highly visible to members.

Experience



Marcid Software Engineer

Rue Gilt Groupe

Jul 2021 - Jan 2023 (1 year 7 months)

- Led the Android Mobile space within RGG
- Apps: Ruelala & Gilt on Google Play/App Store
- · Built member facing systems that allowed members to have a great experience while shopping
- Determined which projects should be highest priority while working with Stakeholders
- Trained and onboarded new engineers (Helped them understand our app, codebase and hierarchy)
- Worked along-side QA, Design and Team Leads in order to make sure the product that we shipped was of the highest quality and to design standards

Software Developer

Sager Electronics

Jun 2019 - Jul 2021 (2 years 2 months)

- Develop modifications for implemented systems used within Business Process Management software used in day-to-day operations
- · Write programs in Java that retrieve information from internal environments via REST API calls
- · Work with Oracle SQL databases to store and retrieve information through programs written in Java and SQR
- Maintain already implemented systems using Version Control Systems GIT
- · Collaborate with other departments to fulfill necessary requirements in a timely fashion

Clinical Desktop Support

Boston University

Feb 2017 - Jun 2019 (2 years 5 months)

- In charge of Student Health Services website administration which used HTML and CSS
- Troubleshot and determined causes of issues
- · Managed junior technicians and assisted with tasks
- Created scripts in Java for Error Log retrieval and debugging
- · Maintained SQL Databases that housed confidential student information

• Stayed up-to-date on software and hardware in order to maintain network integrity

Education



🔄 Boston University Metropolitan College

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science 2014 - 2019

Skills

Kotlin • Android • Java • Software Development • Android Development • Programming • Git